Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name's Erica and I'm here with Marco.
我是Erica，今天和我一起的是Marco。
Marco, hurry up!
Marco，快点！
I'm coming!
来了！
Hurry up, Marco, we've got a lesson.
快点，Marco，我们要上课了。
Okay, I'm here, I'm here.
好了，我来了，我来了。
What did I miss?
我错过了什么？
The lesson.
上课。
All right, sorry about that.
好吧，抱歉。
We have a great lesson for you today.
今天我们为大家准备了一堂很棒的课。
We have an elementary lesson.
我们有一节基础课。
That's right, an elementary lesson about being in a rush and about giving directions when
没错，一节关于匆忙和在车里指路的基础课。
you're in a car.
在车里。
Exactly.
正是。
We're going to listen to two friends who are getting in a car and they're getting ready
我们将听到两个朋友上车准备去某个地方，而且他们非常匆忙。
to go somewhere and they're in a big hurry.
他们非常匆忙。
So let's hurry up and listen to the dialogue.
那我们赶紧听对话吧。
Hurry up, get in.
快点，上车。
All right, man, let's go.
好了，老兄，我们走吧。
Okay, make a left here.
好的，这里左转。
No wait, I meant make a right.
不，等等，我是说右转。
Come on, speed up.
快点，加速。
Geez, what's the rush?
天哪，急什么？
Don't worry about it, just drive.
别担心，只管开。
Oh no, the light is about to change.
哦不，红灯要亮了。
Step on it.
踩油门。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
I'm not going to run a red light.
我不会闯红灯的。
Whatever, just turn right here.
随便，就在这儿右转。
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
这个时间高速会堵车的。
Let's take a side street.
我们走小路吧。
Go on, get out of our way.
快走，别挡路。
Move, move.
让开，让开。
What's your problem?
你有什么毛病？
Geez, having a fit is not going to help.
天哪，发脾气也没用。
Here, I know a shortcut.
我知道一条近路。
Just go down here and we'll cut through Ashburn Heights.
从这边下去，穿过阿什本高地就到了。
Let's go, let's go.
快走，快走。
Watch out for that lady.
小心那位女士。
I'm going as fast as I can.
我已经尽可能快了。
Yes, we made it, 5.58 just before the library closes.
是的，我们赶到了，5点58分，正好在图书馆关门之前。
You're such a geek.
你真是个书呆子。
So they were in a hurry and it was all just to get to the library.
所以他们这么匆忙，就是为了去图书馆。
Well maybe he was late returning a book or something.
也许他是要还书，或者别的什么。
That's a bit dramatic just for returning a book.
就为了还书，这也太夸张了吧。
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, why don't we look at our language takeaway for today.
好了，我们来看看今天的语言要点吧。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, on today's language takeaway we have five words for you today.
好的，今天的语言要点我们有五个单词要讲。
Five really important and useful words that we found in our dialogue.
五个我们在对话中找到的非常重要且有用的单词。
So let's take a look at the first one.
那我们来看看第一个。
Step on it.
踩油门。
So what does it mean when I tell you to step on it?
那么，当我说“踩油门”时是什么意思呢？
Drive faster.
开快点。
Drive faster, right?
开快点，对吧？
Step on it.
踩油门。
Exactly.
没错。
You might also say speed up.
你也可以说“加速”。
Speed up, yes.
加速，是的。
Speed up.
加速。
That's exactly it.
就是这个意思。
Our second word, speed up.
我们的第二个词，加速。
Also means go faster.
也是指开快点。
Go faster.
开快点。
And what about the opposite?
那相反的呢？
You might say slow down.
你可以说“减速”。
Slow down.
减速。
Yeah.
对。
Okay, so speed up and slow down.
好的，所以加速和减速。
So our third word for today is having a fit.
那么今天的第三个词是“发脾气”。
Having a fit.
发脾气。
Well, this is a funny phrase and I think listening to a few examples of this phrase might help
嗯，这是一个有趣的短语，我觉得听几个例子可能会帮助
us understand its meaning a little bit better.
我们更好地理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Geez, you don't need to have a fit.
天哪，你没必要发脾气。
Nothing is going to happen if we're five minutes late.
如果我们迟到五分钟，什么都不会发生。
Example two.
第二个例子。
My boss is going to have a fit if I don't finish this on time.
如果我不按时完成，我的老板会大发雷霆。
Example three.
第三个例子。
I almost had a fit when my boss told me I had to work this weekend.
当老板告诉我这个周末必须加班时，我差点气炸了。
Okay, great example.
好的，很好的例子。
So Erica, why don't you tell me what does it mean when you have a fit?
那么埃里卡，你来说说“have a fit”是什么意思？
It means you get really angry and you can't control your emotions.
意思是你非常生气，无法控制自己的情绪。
So maybe you start screaming and maybe some steam comes out of your ears.
所以你可能会开始尖叫，甚至气得冒烟。
Okay, that's having a fit.
好的，那就是“have a fit”。
Exactly.
没错。
Excellent.
太好了。
Okay, let's take a look at our next word now.
好的，现在我们来看下一个词。
Cut through.
When you cut through something, it means you just go through.
当你“cut through”某物时，意思就是直接穿过去。
Go through.
穿过去。
Yeah, quite simple.
是的，很简单。
It gives you the idea that you go through something quickly.
它给人一种快速穿过的感觉。
Quickly.
快速地。
So I can say, let's cut through the park.
所以可以说，我们穿过公园吧。
Yep, or let's cut through the backyard.
是的，或者我们穿过后院吧。
Okay, go through.
好的，穿过去。
And this takes us to our last word for today, shortcut.
这就引出了我们今天最后一个词，“shortcut”。
Shortcut.
Cut. This is a really common word and not many people know about it.
这是一个很常见的词，但很多人不了解它。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
It's two simple words that when you fit them together, the meaning changes.
它由两个简单的词组成，但组合在一起后意思就变了。
It's a great example of this real English we talk about.
这是我们所说的地道英语的一个很好的例子。
And it means to take a shorter way somewhere.
它的意思是走一条更短的路去某地。
Exactly.
没错。
So if I take a shortcut, I go the short way.
所以如果我走捷径，我就走了一条近路。
Okay, so going back just a little bit to cut through.
好的，那我们稍微回顾一下“cut through”。
If I cut through the park, that's basically a shortcut.
如果我穿过公园，那基本上就是一条捷径。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, now it's clear.
好了，现在清楚了。
Now it's time to listen to our dialogue again, but this time it's going to be slower so then
现在是时候再听一遍我们的对话了，但这次会慢一些，这样
we can understand all these words that we've just talked about.
我们就能理解刚才讨论的所有单词了。
Hurry up, get in.
快点，上车。
I'm in.
我上来了。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Okay.
好的。
Make a left here.
在这儿左转。
No wait, I meant make a right.
不，等等，我是说右转。
Come on, speed up.
快点，加速。
Geez, what's the rush?
天哪，急什么？
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
Just drive.
只管开。
Oh no, the light is about to change.
哦不，红灯要亮了。
Step on it.
踩油门。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
I'm not going to run a red light.
我不会闯红灯的。
Whatever.
随便吧。
Just turn right here.
就在这儿右转。
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
这个时间段高速会堵车的。
Let's take a side street.
我们走小路吧。
Go on, get out of our way.
快走，别挡路。
Move, move.
让开，让开。
What's your problem?
你有什么毛病？
Geez, having a fit is not going to help.
天哪，发脾气也没用。
Here, I know a shortcut.
我知道一条近路。
Just go down here and we'll cut through Ashburn Heights.
从这儿下去，我们穿过阿什本高地。
Let's go, let's go.
快走，快走。
Watch out for that lady.
小心那位女士。
I'm going as fast as I can.
我已经开得最快了。
Yes, we made it.
太好了，我们赶到了。
5.58, just before the library closes.
5点58分，正好在图书馆关门之前。
You're such a geek.
你真是个书呆子。
Okay, well I think that was a lot more clear this time.
好了，我觉得这次清楚多了。
You know, there was some great language in that dialogue and I would like to look at
你知道，那段对话里有些很棒的语言，我想看看
how we can put it together.
我们怎么把它们组合起来。
Putting it together.
组合起来。
Okay, so today on putting it together, we have three phrases for you.
好的，今天在“组合起来”环节，我们准备了三个短语。
And we're going to show you how you can use these phrases like a native speaker.
我们会展示如何像母语者一样使用这些短语。
Okay, so all of these phrases we heard in the dialogue, why don't we start with the
好的，所有这些短语我们都在对话中听到了，不如我们从
first one?
第一个开始？
Make a.
左转。
So in the dialogue, they say make a left here.
所以在对话中，他们说在这里左转。
Yeah, and we can extend this phrase to say make a right.
是的，我们可以把这个短语扩展成右转。
That would be the equivalent of saying turn left.
这相当于说向左转。
Or turn right.
或者向右转。
Turn right.
向右转。
And there's one more.
还有一个。
Make a u-turn.
掉头。
Exactly.
没错。
That means turn the car 180 degrees all the way around.
意思是把车180度完全转过来。
Make a u-turn.
掉头。
So make a left, make a right, make a u-turn.
所以左转、右转、掉头。
If you're ever in a taxi and you're telling the taxi driver where to go, this is the perfect
如果你在出租车里，告诉司机去哪里，这是最完美的
way.
方式。
Make a left here, make a right there.
这里左转，那里右转。
Okay, so let's move to our second phrase and it is, are you nuts?
好的，那我们来看第二个短语，就是：你疯了吗？
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
So this is a great way of saying.
这是一种很好的表达方式。
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
Are you insane?
你神经病吗？
Are you mad?
你疯了吗？
So when would we use a phrase like this?
那我们什么时候会用这样的短语呢？
If somebody has a bad idea that you don't agree with, you would say, are you crazy?
如果有人有个你不同意的坏主意，你会说：你疯了吗？
Or are you nuts?
或者你疯了吗？
So Marco, let's stop this podcast right now.
所以Marco，我们现在就停止这个播客吧。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
Okay, I think that's a good example of how we can use this phrase.
好的，我觉得这是个很好的例子，说明我们如何使用这个短语。
Yes.
是的。
So are you nuts?
所以你疯了吗？
Are you insane?
你神经病吗？
Are you mad?
你疯了吗？
So let's listen to some examples of are you nuts?
我们来听一些关于“你疯了吗”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
You want to get married now?
你现在想结婚？
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
You only met her three weeks ago.
你三周前才认识她。
Example two.
例子二。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
I'm not going to cheat on the exam.
我不会在考试中作弊的。
What if I get caught?
万一我被抓了呢？
So I think that's clear and now we can move to our third phrase, which is, let's take
所以我想这已经很清楚了，现在我们可以进入第三个短语，那就是，我们走
a side street.
一条小路。
Let's take a side street.
我们走一条小路。
Again, so if you're in a taxi, this is a great way to suggest a route or suggest a direction.
同样，如果你在出租车里，这是建议路线或方向的好方法。
So we can take this phrase and extend it out with a few more words.
我们可以用这个短语，再扩展几个词。
We might say, let's take Wilson Avenue.
我们可以说，我们走威尔逊大道。
Or let's take the highway.
或者我们走高速公路。
So let's take a side street.
所以我们走一条小路。
Let's take Wilson Avenue.
我们走威尔逊大道。
Let's take the freeway.
我们走高速公路。
Okay, so now let's take a listen to this dialogue a third time at its normal speed and now you
好的，现在让我们以正常速度第三次听这段对话，现在你
can understand everything that's in this dialogue.
能理解这段对话中的所有内容了。
Hurry up, get in.
快点，上车。
Hi man, let's go.
嗨，老兄，我们走。
Okay, make a left here.
好的，这里左转。
No wait, I meant make a right.
不，等等，我是说右转。
Come on, speed up.
快点，加速。
Geez, what's the rush?
天哪，急什么？
Don't worry about it, just drive.
别担心，只管开车。
Oh no, the light is about to change.
哦不，红灯要亮了。
Step on it.
踩油门。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
I'm not going to run a red light.
我不会闯红灯的。
Whatever, just turn right here.
随便，就在这里右转。
The freeway will be packed at this hour.
这个时间高速公路会很堵。
Let's take a side street.
我们走一条小路。
Go on, get out of our way.
快，别挡道。
Move, move.
让开，让开。
What's your problem?
你有什么毛病？
Geez, having a fit is not going to help.
天哪，发脾气也没用。
Here, I know a shortcut.
我知道一条近路。
Let's go down here and we'll cut through Ashburn Heights.
我们从这里下去，穿过阿什本高地。
Let's go, let's go.
走吧，走吧。
Watch out for that lady.
小心那位女士。
I'm going as fast as I can.
我已经开得最快了。
Yes, we made it.
是的，我们赶到了。
5.58 just before the library closes.
5点58分，正好在图书馆关门之前。
You're such a geek.
你真是个书呆子。
Well this dialogue is all about driving, right?
嗯，这段对话是关于开车的，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
In North America, where both of us are from, driving is everything.
在北美，我们俩都来自那里，开车就是一切。
Everybody has a car.
每个人都有车。
When did you get a car?
你什么时候买的车？
My car I got when I was like maybe 19.
我大概19岁的时候买了车。
Really?
真的吗？
But I learned how to drive and I was driving already by the age of 16.
但我16岁就学会开车并开始开了。
Yeah, that's the thing.
是啊，就是这样。
In many countries you have to wait until I think you're 18 to drive, but in North America
在很多国家，你得等到18岁才能开车，但在北美
everyone has a driver's license by the time they're 16 years old.
每个人16岁就有驾照了。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
Because everything is so far away that you need a car.
因为所有地方都太远了，你需要车。
Yeah, it's a lot less likely to have subways or trains to travel by in North America.
是啊，北美很少有地铁或火车可以乘坐。
All right, so now you have all the tools necessary to give directions the next time you're in
好了，现在你掌握了所有必要的工具，下次在
a car or in a taxi.
车里或出租车里指路时就能用了。
Well everyone, I really hope you enjoyed this lesson.
好了，各位，我真的希望你们喜欢这节课。
Now I want to remind you all to come to our EnglishPod website at EnglishPod.com and here
现在我想提醒大家，来我们的EnglishPod网站EnglishPod.com，在这里
you'll find a lot of tools to help you understand our podcasts better.
你们会找到很多工具来帮助更好地理解我们的播客。
So with that, until next time, this is goodbye.
那么，下次再见，拜拜。